{
    "id": "bbdc05c1e5b449ac86d6d85908feac5b",
    "title": "Identifying Conditional Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "3bebbe0785a14009b07ff9aabbbc289f",
            "title": "Identifying Conditionals",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "If I don't drink coffee in the afternoon, I feel sleepy.",
                    "description": "In the zero conditional, we use the simple present tense in both the clauses.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Zero conditional",
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I will tell her if I meet her.",
                    "description": "In the first conditional, we use will + infinitive in the main clause and simple present tense in the if-clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Zero conditional",
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I would have helped if I had been there.",
                    "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Zero conditional",
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you want to play a musical instrument, you have to practice.",
                    "description": "In the zero conditional, we use the simple present tense in both the clauses.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Zero conditional",
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If I have enough time tomorrow, I will come and see you.",
                    "description": "In the first conditional, we use will + infinitive in the main clause and simple present tense in the if-clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Zero conditional",
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you eat too much, you get fat.",
                    "description": "In the zero conditional, we use the simple present tense in both the clauses.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Zero conditional",
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "What would you do if you lost your job?",
                    "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Zero conditional",
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you had run a bit faster, you would have won.",
                    "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Zero conditional",
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "If I were you, I would buy it as soon as possible.",
                    "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Zero conditional",
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "If he had gone to university, he would have got a better job.",
                    "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Zero conditional",
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "I will be surprised if he doesn't win.",
                    "description": "In the first conditional, we use will + infinitive in the main clause and simple present tense in the if-clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Zero conditional",
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "If anyone complains, we will deal with it promptly.",
                    "description": "In the first conditional, we use will + infinitive in the main clause and simple present tense in the if-clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Zero conditional",
                        "First conditional",
                        "Second conditional",
                        "Third conditional"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}